

CONTACT

- Ahmedabad, India
- +91 823-804-3072
- ☑ dhvanitjakhaniya@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/sachin-patel-695858154

SKILLS

2D Drafting and 3D Modelling

Observational Skill

Presentation Skill

E-Mail Communication

Public Communication

Willingness to travel

Team Work

SOFTWARE SKILLS

AutoCAD

Microsoft Office

Mastercam

Autodesk Inventor

Solidworks

SACHIN JAKHANIYA

Design Engineer

ABOUT ME

Solutions-orientated Diploma Mechanical Engineer with 8.5 years career experience providing cost effective solutions. Highly adept in technical writing and drawing with project management capabilities. Possesses very good communication and analytical skills. High ability to work effectively as team member or independently.



WORK EXPERIENCE

DESIGN ENGINEER

Jan - 2015 to Present

Arvind anticor Ltd, Ahmedabad

(Exporter of superior range of multifarious products such as Galvanizing plant, Pickling Plants, Pickling Tanks and Anti-Corrosive Equipment made from various Industrial Thermoplastics)

Interacting with Sales Team/ Customers to get complete information regarding creation of designs for projects.

Visiting sites wherever required to understand special requirements of the site.

Co-coordinating and collecting drawings/ measurements from site.

Getting preliminary drawing prepared within maximum 48 hours from receipt of measurements as per details.

As per application, managing and preparing 3D design layout, concept layout, preparing BOM, Final design and maintain designs process through the

Provide detailed designs and developments of the product.

Familiar with modern computer hardware, software, and cloud sharing services

Experience in valves, pipes & fittings projects.

) DESIGN ENGINEER

Nov - 2013 to Dec - 2014

Abellon Clean Energy Ltd, Ahmedabad

(Pioneer in the Waste-to-Energy sector in India)

Managed all phases of the design process for a multitude of products, components, parts, assemblies, including drafting, dimensioning, and documenting results.

Known for quality excellence and a "do-it-right-the-first-time" design standard.

Making eco-equipment drawings that can effectively replace LPG, Diesel and other fossil fuel-based systems across a broad spectrum of applications, especially in the commercial and industrial energy generation, heating and cooking segments, and for co-firing with fossil fuels such as coal and lignite in power plants.

Commended for strengths in defining, assessing and satisfying product specifications and manufacturability concerns.

Reduce product costs and improve design performance by working with engineers.

ORGANIZATION

Arvind anticor Limited (JAN-2015 to Present)

Abellon Cleanenergy Ltd (Nov-2013 to Dec-2014)

Arham Pump (Aug-2012 to Oct-2013)

HOBBIES



MUSIC



SPORT



TRAVEL



INTERNET

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH

GUJARATI

HINDI

REFERENCE

AVAILABLE ON DEMAND

TRAINEE ENGINEER

Aug - 2012 to Oct - 2013

Arham pump, Ahmedabad

(Arham is a one stop solution for all kinds of domestic pressure pump requirements)

Be open to learn new things and enjoy the learning journey.

Accept lawful instruction given by you in regard to work, training and instruction in the workplace.

Working closely with staff to foster professional values and build good relationships

Observing existing strategies and techniques and offering suggestions for improvement

Working experience as a quality, production,

Maintenance works,

Working on pump performance testing of load & noload, computer generated pump parameter diagrams soft sheets.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

Diploma Mechanical

Government Polytechnic College,

Porabandar (GTU)

(Affiliated to Gujarat Technological University (GTU)

with First Class

C.A.M.D. 2006-2008 Computer Aided Mechanical Drafting

(Affiliated to Technical Examination Board,

Gandhinagar (TEB) with First Class

10TH STANDARD

R A PATEL BOY'S HIGHSCHOOL,wadhwan

City, Surendranagar

Secondary School Education from G.S.E.B. with 58%



CERTIFICATES

LCC InfoTech Is The Front - Runner & Amongst The First In IT Education Training In India.

OM ENGINEERING Autodesk Authorized Training CAD Center.